It's a dead end.
إنه طريق مسدود.
Your Majesty, you played
جلالة الملك ، لقد لعبت
a good chess game.
لعبة شطرنج جيدة.
Have you really thought it through?
هل فكرت حقا في ذلك؟
I have no regrets.
ليس لدي أي ندم.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
I know,
أنا أعرف،
The way to be a king.
الطريق الى ان تكون ملكا.
You must care about the people.
يجب أن تهتم بالناس.
Check and balance the imperial court.
تحقق وتوازن في البلاط الإمبراطوري.
His Majesty is a master now.
جلالة الملك هو سيد الآن.
Goodbye, Wei Shangzhi.
وداعا ، وي Shangzhi.
Somebody
شخص ما
Prepare the imperial edict.
تحضير المرسوم الإمبراطوري.
His Lordship is wise,
سيادته حكيمة ،
Chuangu will not disgrace his life.
لن تشوانغو عار حياته.
Here comes the imperial edict.
هنا يأتي المرسوم الإمبراطوري.
Bongtian carried the emperor's edict
حمل Bongtian مرسوم الإمبراطور
and said,
و قال،
Defending the title for taking bribes and breaking the law,
الدفاع عن حق الرشوة ومخالفة القانون ،
embezzling military food,
اختلاس الطعام العسكري ،
That led to the tragic death of Ye Army.
أدى ذلك إلى الموت المأساوي لجيش يي.
Wei Shangzhi is brutal
Wei Shangzhi وحشي
and unworthy of virtue,
ولا يستحق الفضيلة ،
They commit adultery, plunder,
يرتكبون الزنا والنهب ،
and do all kinds of evil,
وتفعل كل أنواع الشر ،
Take away the marquis
خذ بعيدا المركيز
and put him in jail,
ووضعه في السجن ،
He will be executed on another day
سيتم إعدامه في يوم آخر
as a warning to others.
كتحذير للآخرين.
Bai Zhi
باي تشي
is the daughter of General Ye Shangyu.
هي ابنة الجنرال يي شانغيو.
Lord Yongle, Duke Jingbei's Mansion
اللورد يونجل ، قصر الدوق جينغبى
will be appointed as the county's mansion.
سيتم تعيين قصر المقاطعة.
Allow him to marry Wei Shangzhi and Bai Qinglang,
اسمح له بالزواج من وي شانغجي وباي تشينغلانغ ،
the second son of the Li Bai family,
الابن الثاني لعائلة لي باي ،
Allow him to restore his real name
السماح له باستعادة اسمه الحقيقي
to General Lin Feng Dingyuan,
إلى الجنرال لين فنغ دينجيوان ،
Choose another day
اختر يومًا آخر
to go to Xiliang.
للذهاب إلى Xiliang.
Wait.
انتظر.
He raped, killed, plundered,
اغتصب وقتل ونهب
and did all kinds of evil,
وعملوا كل أنواع الشر ،
How did you know
كيف عرفت
about these charges?
حول هذه الاتهامات؟
At this time,
في هذا الوقت،
what does it matter if there's one more and one less?
ما الذي يهم إذا كان هناك واحد آخر وأخرى أقل؟
Take him away.
يأخذه بعيدا.
No.
رقم.
Your Ladyship,
سيدتك ،
what will happen to him?
ماذا سيحدث له؟
You'll die.
سوف تموت.
You're quite skilled.
أنت ماهر جدًا.
I'm flattered, General Lin.
أنا أشعر بالإطراء ، الجنرال لين.
Don't think that if you confess,
لا تعتقد أنه إذا اعترفت ،
you can avoid the pain of flesh and blood.
يمكنك تجنب آلام اللحم والدم.
The debts you owe the Wei family,
الديون التي تدين بها لعائلة وي ،
will be paid by you.
سوف تدفع من قبلك.
Does it hurt?
هل تؤلم؟
Back then, Ye Jiajun suffered a hundred times
في ذلك الوقت ، عانت يي جياجون مائة مرة
as much as you did.
بقدر ما فعلت.
A thousand times,
الف مرة،
ten thousand times.
عشرة آلاف مرة.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
Is there anything else you want to say?
هل هناك أي شيء آخر تريد أن تقوله؟
Take good care of
اعتني جيدا ب
Zhi,
زي ،
Don't bother.
لا تهتم.
The Lin family has been born for the Ye family for generations.
ولدت عائلة لين لعائلة يي لأجيال.
I was born for Zhi.
لقد ولدت لشي.
After killing the guard of Xiliang,
بعد قتل حارس Xiliang ،
Makino
ماكينو
Don't you have anything else to say?
أليس لديك أي شيء آخر لتقوله؟
Old Man Wei,
العجوز وي
you handed over the whole Zhou Dynasty to me.
لقد سلمت لي أسرة تشو بأكملها.
You tricked me for so long.
لقد خدعتني لفترة طويلة.
I'll pay you back.
سأعيد لك ما دفعته.
From now on, we don't owe each other anything.
من الآن فصاعدًا ، لا ندين لبعضنا البعض بأي شيء.
It's fair, right?
هذا عادل ، صحيح؟
You little brat!
أنت شقي صغير!
Stand still!
تراوح مكانها!
It's not fair.
ليس عادلا.
My Lord,
ربي،
Chuanxiao has brought back the secret message from Qingliang.
أعاد Chuanxiao الرسالة السرية من Qingliang.
Forgive Kawahiro......
سامح كواهيرو ......
You must know the truth.
يجب أن تعرف الحقيقة.